Brayden Babbitt

Technologist | Designer | Communicator

CONTACT

Address: 7235 North Red Clover Way, Eagle

Mountain, UT. 84005

Email: brayden@babbitts.net Phone: (303) 856-4271

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/brayden-

babbitt/

Instagram: @braydentbabbitt Facebook: @braydentbabbitt

SKILLS

Mobile and Web Development

- Flutter / Dart
- VBA
- SQL
- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- Java

Design

- Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere, After Effects)
- UX & UI design (Figma, Adobe XD)

Project Management & QA

Digital Marketing

- LinkedIn advertising
- · Facebook/Instagram advertising
- · Google Search and Display ads

Audiovisual Media Production

- Video editing
- Photo editing
- Basic 2D animation
- · Audio recording and production
- · Music composition and production

Public Speaking

- Live news interviews
- Sloan Speech Competition runner-up

Fluent in Spanish

Military Spanish translation certification

STATEMENT



Though my education and much of my work experience is in marketing, digital advertising, communications, and public relations, my true passion is in tech. I have been programming since I was 14. I spend much of my free time designing and developing my own mobile and web applications, as well as writing automations to make my life easier.

One of my favorite things to do is the world's #1 fear: public speaking. I also love teaching, tutoring, and sharing my passions with anyone who will listen.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2021 Brigham Young University (BYU)

BA in Communications: Public Relations

WORK HISTORY

2021 - Present ZooWho, Inc.

Chief Marketing Officer / Chief Technology Officer

Managed a team of 8 developers across 3 contracting agencies to develop new features, fix bugs, and successfully roll out the Nouri mobile and web applications. Designed UI and clearly communicated UX flows to the development team to ensure attention to detail and customer expectations were met. Managed all internal technology services, such as email routing, domain DNS management, custom email signatures, and calendar scheduling tools.

Led a major re-branding of the company's main products. Represented the company in live interviews and media placements. Interviewed and made hiring decisions for marketing personnel and worked closely with new hires to ensure their success at ZooWho. Designed and managed the ZooWho and Nouri websites and led SEO and advertising efforts to expedite user acquisition.

2020 - 2021 B2Linked

Account Manager

Optimized digital ad placements, creatives, copy, and adspend for 8 clients on LinkedIn's PPC advertising platform. Managed client relationships to assure timeliness, efficiency, and client satisfaction, as well as increase in adspend. Trained junior account managers to manage client relationships independently.

Created Excel VBA automations that increased efficiency of bulk ad creation using LinkedIn's advertising API by 50%.

2019 - 2020 ZooWho Inc.

Director of Communications

Led marketing team efforts to increase total user count from ~100 to ~17,000 through digital advertising, SEO efforts, and earning media placements. Worked intimately with business leaders to develop design and communication strategies for VC funding pitches and UX/UI projects.

2018 - 2019 Utah National Guard

Spanish Language Linguist, Civilian

Translated evidence from Spanish to English and prepared all documentation for court use. Acheived a military certification in Spanish translation with an excellence in quality.